Damilola Oyeniyi

damilolaoyeniyi13@gmail.com | 09036818841 | Ilorin, Kwara

damioyeniyi.netlify.app/ | www.linkedin.com/in/damilola-oyeniyi-97805b23a/ | github.com/grzdev

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Seasoned frontend engineer with roughly 2 years of frontend programming experience. I have a strong aptitude for detecting and correcting faults and defects in codebases, with a particular focus on React and TypeScript. I consistently strive to identify methods to improve applications and ensure the successful execution of my suggestions. To produce aesthetically pleasing and intuitive interfaces, I maintain a proactive approach towards learning and remain up-to-date with the latest web development tools and techniques.

EDUCATION

University of Ilorin September 2024

Bachelor of Science in Geology and Mineral Sciences

Kwara, Nigeria

WORK EXPERIENCE

VENNDO Marketplace April 2023 – July 2023

Frontend Developer Remote

- Slashed the estimated time to complete web pages by 30% by implementing designs created by UI/UX teams at a fast pace while conducting code reviews.
- Restructured the company's codebase to enable smooth readability for newly employed developers while writing comments for better understanding.

Swift Medispark August 2022 – January 2023

Frontend Developer Remote

- Visualized the list of hospitals that use the company's EMR by building a web page with React and seamlessly integrating a restful API to the page while fixing bugs on the main site.
- Increased the EMRs performance by 10% by removing unused functionalities in the codebase while improving the UI.

Zuri x Ingressive For Good

May 2022 – August 2022

Frontend Developer

Remote

- Exceeded expectations by offering frontend solutions and fulfilling project requirements, as well as executing assigned tasks on time and efficiently in order to meet deadlines.
- Researched various programming languages recommended by senior programmers in order to better my coding skills while collaborating with design teams to create stable web sites.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

4 Youth By Youth August 2020 – Present

Research Facilitator

Lagos, Nigeria

- Recruited individuals who could benefit from the program and provided them with HIV kits for their health and awareness.
- Persuaded participants to make educated health decisions and visit the clinic as needed, while
 maintaining constant connection to share information, answer queries, and provide other resources as
 needed.

SKILLS

Skills: Javascript, React, Typescript, Redux, HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Chakra UI, Firebase, Git

CERTIFICATIONS

Ingressive for Good x Zuri Training

August 2022